craftylife.net 2019-12-13

# TOS/Privacy Policy

**TERMS OF SERVICE and Privacy Policy **Updated May 29nd, 2018****

## Who we are

Our website address is: https://www.craftylife.net.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Contact forms

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

## Who we share your data with

We may share your information with third parties when you explicitly authorize us to share your information.

Additionally, the Website may use third-party service providers service various aspects of the Website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policies. The Website currently uses the following third-party service providers:

  * Google Analytics – this service tracks Website usage and provides information such as referring websites and user actions on the Website. Google Analytics may capture your IP address, but no other personal information is captured by Google Analytics.
  * Convert Kit – this service is used for delivery of email updates and newsletters. We store your name and email address for purposes of delivering such communications.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

## Your contact information

Email: admin@craftylife.net

## Additional information

### How we protect your data and data breach procedures we have in place

Securi Firewall is used to protect your data and mine. – https://sucuri.net

### What third parties we receive data from

At this time, your personal information is not shared with any other third-party applications. This list may be amended from time to time in the Website’s sole discretion.

Except when required by law, we will not sell, distribute, or reveal your email addresses or other personal information without your consent; however, we may disclose or transfer personal information collected through the Website to third parties who acquire all or a portion of our business, which may be the result of a merger, consolidation, or purchase of all or a portion of our assets, or in connection with any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding brought by or against us.

 ** _ANONYMOUS DATA_**

From time to time, we may use anonymous data, which does not identify you alone, or when combined with data from other parties. This type of anonymous data may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. Examples of this anonymous data may include analytics or information collected from cookies.

 ** _PUBLICLY VISIBLE INFORMATION_**

If you create a user profile on the Website or leave a comment, certain information may be publicly visible.

 ** _COOKIES_**

The Website uses cookies to store visitors’ preferences, record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, ensure that visitors are not repeatedly sent the same banner ads, customize Website content based on visitors’ browser type or other information that the visitor sends. Cookies may also be used by third-party services, such as Google Analytics, as described herein.

Users may, at any time, prevent the setting of cookies, by the Website, by using a corresponding setting of your internet browser and may thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Furthermore, already set cookies may be deleted at any time via an Internet browser or other software programs. This is possible in all popular Internet browsers. However, if users deactivate the setting of cookies in your Internet browser, not all functions of our Website may be entirely usable.

 ** _ADVERTISING_**

 **Display Ads  
**We may use third-party advertising companies to serve content and advertisements when you visit the Website, which may use cookies. No personally identifiable information is shared with the Website’s ad providers.

This Site is affiliated with ROI Influencer Media  for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site.  ROI Influencer Media uses standard and widely-available tools for the placement and serving of ads, including those provided by Google, Inc. and its affiliates. We publish interest-based advertisements on the Site; that is, ads that are tailored to reflect your interests. To help understand your interests, ROI Influencer Media, Google and our other advertising partners will track your behavior on our website and on other websites across the Internet using cookies.

A cookie is a file containing an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. Cookies may be either “persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is closed.  Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

By using this Site, you consent to the use of such cookies and the sharing of data captured by such cookies with ROI Influencer Media, Google, and our other third-party partners. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). Again, you can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/). However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained.

For European Economic Area Residents

If you reside in a country in the European Economic Area (EEA), then under the GDPR and applicable data protection laws you have the rights, among other things, to access your personal data, have us erase it, and/or restrict its further processing.  If you wish to access or delete your personal data (if any) maintained by us or ROI Influencer Media related to advertising on the Site, you can contact me, admin@craftylife.net.

 **Retargeting Ads  
**From time to time, the Website may engage in remarketing efforts with third-party companies, such as Google, Facebook, or Instagram, in order to market the Website. These companies use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the Website.

 **Sponsored Content Tracking Pixels  
**This Website may engage in sponsored campaigns with various influencer networks, brands, and agencies, including Facebokk, Twitter and Pinterest. All sponsored content is duly disclosed in accordance with the FTC’s requirements. From time to time, these sponsored campaigns utilize tracking pixels (aka web beacons), which may contain cookies to collect data regarding usage and audience. This information is collected by the sponsoring company to track the results of the campaign. No personally identifiable information collected by the Website is used in conjunction with these tracking pixels.

 **Affiliate Program Participation  
**The Website may engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the Website. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions.

My Crafty Life is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and links to Amazon.com.  As part of this Amazon Associates program, the Website will post customized links, provided by Amazon, to track the referrals to their website. This program utilizes cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales.

 **Newsletters**  
On the Website, you may subscribe to our newsletter, which may be used for advertising purposes. All newsletters sent may contain tracking pixels. The pixel is embedded in emails and allows an analysis of the success of online marketing campaigns. Because of these tracking pixels, we may see if and when you open an email and which links within the email you click. Also, this allows the Website to adapt the content of future newsletters to the interests of the user. This behavior will not be passed on to third parties.

 ** _RIGHTS RELATED TO YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION_**

 **Opt-out**  – You may opt-out of future email communications by following the unsubscribe links in our emails. You may also notify us at admin@craftylife.net to be removed from our mailing list.

 **Access**  – You may access the personal information we have about you by submitting a request to admin@craftylife.net

 **Amend**  – You may contact us at admin@craftylife.net to amend or update your personal information.

 **Forget**  – In certain situations, you may request that we erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to admin@craftylife.net

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law.

 ** _SENSITIVE PERSONAL INFORMATION_**

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to the Website. This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, criminal background, or trade union memberships. If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

 ** _CHILDREN’S INFORMATION_**

The Website does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. If a parent or guardian believes that the Website has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 16 in its database, please contact us immediately at admin@craftylife.net and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

 ** _CONTACT INFORMATION_**

At any time, please contact us at admin@craftylife.net for questions related to this Privacy Policy.

Please scroll down for my use of Ads policy.

* * *

My Crafty Life is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to Amazon.com

#### To see my other connections and partnerships visit [My Connections](http://www.craftylife.net/my-connections/)

* * *

 **Giveaway Policy** – I am not responsible for lost or un-redeemed prizes. All terms listed in the entry form are enforced and verified. Unless otherwise noted, winners have 48 hours to contact me by whatever means necessary. There are multiple ways on this site to contact me. I always respond to let my winners know that their email was received. If you do not receive an email from me, assume I didn’t receive that email and try to contact me an alternative way within the allotted time.

If I do not hear from you I will assume that you are not interested in the prize and pick a new winner. I have no way to verify if you received the email and I can not just take your word for it. I need to be fair to all that enter these giveaways. I put a lot of work into these giveaways and I can not spend any extra time tracking people down.

* * *

 **Updated On January 3th, 2018**

 **Please note:  any giveaway winner is emailed and given 24-48 hours to respond. If I do not hear from you within that time limit I will redraw. I usually respond to your email within 6 hours to confirm I received your response. If you do not hear from me, feel free to contact me on Twitter or Facebook to let me know. Email can be tricky. **

Entry into any of my giveaways signals compliance with these terms.

* * *

 _ **My reviews are ALWAYS tried and true.**_

 _ **I do not post for any company I do not have experience with or have researched.**_

 **My Ethics Policy:**

  * I will tell the truth.
  * I will write deliberately and with accuracy.
  * I will acknowledge and correct mistakes promptly.
  * I will preserve the original post, using notations to show where I have made changes so as to maintain the integrity of my publishing.
  * I will never delete a post.{Unless it’s outdated or obsolete}
  * I will not delete comments unless they are offensive in language{swearing},spam or off-topic.
  * I will reply to emails and comments when appropriate, and do so as promptly as possible.
  * I will strive for high quality with every post – including basic spellchecking. I am dyslexic however, I do my best.
  * I will stay on topic.
  * I will disagree with other opinions respectfully.
  * I will link to online references and original source materials as directly as possible.
  * I will disclose conflicts of interest.
  * I will keep private issues and topics private, since discussing private issues would jeopardize my personal and work relationships.

* * *

For information on advertising, sponsorship, reviews, and giveaways please visit my [Advertising](http://www.craftylife.net/termsofservice/advertise/) page.

* * *

 **Regarding the ads on My Crafty Life:** I accept forms of advertising from different forms of advertisers in order to offset giveaway, website and hosting costs. I have researched them to MY fullest extent and to all of my capabilities. Use your own judgment. Please refer to my [Terms of Service/Privacy policy](https://docs.google.com/Doc?docid=0Abn2fkFCUpxiZGY4cnJ2d3ZfMzBkN3M5dGNmZA&hl=en) for further details. Use of this site implies compliance with these terms. Thank you.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. You can view, delete or add interest categories associated with your browser by visiting: [https://adssettings.google.com](https://adssettings.google.com/). You can also opt out of the network cookie using those settings or using the Network Advertising Initiative’s multi-cookie opt-out mechanism at: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/). However, these opt-out mechanisms themselves use cookies, and if you clear the cookies from your browser your opt-out will not be maintained.

* * *

 **Contact Me:**

email any questions/comments [here](https://jenr329.typeform.com/to/bVTNdP)

 _~Jen @craftymomof3_

* * *
